GABRIELLE WALD

(617) 413-0253 • gabibmello@gmail.com • LinkedIn: gabriellewald • GitHub: gabriellewald

SUMMARY

Data Scientist interested in surfacing insights from data. Experience creating accessible visualization and predictive models for a wide range of applications. Deep interest in experimentation, the scientific method and the use of technology to generate positive impact, improve services, and discover solutions.

EDUCATION

MIT Professional Education

2021 - 2021

- Data Science and Machine Learning: Making Data-Driven Decisions
- **Relevant coursework**: Regression and Prediction, Hypothesis Testing and Classification, The Use of Modern Regression for Causal Inference.

University of California Davis

2017 - 2020

- Bachelor of Science in Cognitive Science
- Computer Science and Neuroscience emphasis
- **Relevant coursework**: Applied Statistics, Biostatistics, Statistical Analysis in R, Linear Algebra, Research Methods, Data Structures and Algorithms in Python, Object Oriented Programming in Python

University of Hawaii | Kapiolani Community College

2013 - 2015

- Associate of Arts in Liberal Arts, 4.0 GPA Valedictorian
- Applied Linguistics Concentration
- Leadership: Vice President of Scholarship at Phi Theta Kappa Alpha Kappa Psi Chapter

EXPERIENCE

Senior Analyst, Known Global

Feb 2022 - Present

Promoted April 2023

- Build ML models and run SQL queries on database with hundreds of millions of data entries to analyze consumer
- Work independently to complete requests end-to-end, supporting both internal and external stakeholders
- Prepare, analyze and visualize consumer data to support analyzes, customer requests, and product R&D
- Collaborate with clients to help them solve problems using data

Data Science Fellow, Springboard School of Data

Sep 2020 - Sep 2021

600+ hours of hands-on coursework, with 1:1 industry expert mentorship

- Created machine learning model to predict student performance in CA K-12 public schools using regression models
- Performed feature engineering with over 7 million data points to prepare dataset for classification models
- Formulated/ tested hypotheses to understand relationship between target and explanatory vars
- Applied A/B testing to understand change in design for a media platform
- Found and transformed several files to construct unique datasets

Data Analytics and AI Fellow, DS4A Empowerment Program | Correlation One

Oct 2020 - Feb 2021

Merit-based fellowship with 5% acceptance rate led by Harvard Prof. Natesh Pillai

- Co-created capstone project to understand financial impact in CA K-12 public schools
- Ran regression models to determine variables of impact and identify confounding factors
- Performed t-test and chi-square analysis for hypothesis testing
- Conducted exploratory data analysis and created meaningful plots to identify patterns

Data Analyst at SELF-Lab, University of California Davis

May 2019 - Jul 2020

- Ran descriptives and constructed visualization for research in collaboration with the World Bank
- Organized and cleaned data with over 63,000 data points in R / Excel to prepare data for analysis
- Collaborated with researchers and participated in planning meetings
- Ran Random Forest model to understand intervention effectiveness

Research Assistant, UC Davis Center for Mind and Brain

Aug 2017 – Jul 2019

- Carried out data collection for behavioral studies
- Ran eye-tracking software SMI and coded infant behavior data
- Screened participants and followed IRB guidelines for research projects
- Trained new RAs on lab procedures and collaborated with P.I., PhD students, and fellow researchers

Vice President of Scholarship, PTK Honor Society International

Jan 2015 – Jan 2016

- Partnered with organizations for collaboration on campus projects
- Led weekly meetings with society members to address action items
- Organized and presented induction ceremony to welcome new inductees

PROJECTS

Auction Fraud Detection August 2021

Exploratory Data Analysis | Feature Engineering

- Performed feature engineering to predict auction fraud through classification machine learning models
- Conducted exploratory data analysis of auction data to understand variables importance and create new features

Predicting Test Performance in California Public Schools

May 2021

Education Project | Machine Learning Models

This project was an in-depth investigation of factors possibly affecting school performance

- Designed predictive model to project the percentage of students passing standard tests in CA K-12 public schools
- Modeled training data with linear regression, lasso, decision tree, random forest, and gradient boosting
- Combined multiple datasets and tested hypotheses to address open ended questions

SKILLS

- Programming: Python, numpy, pandas, matplotlib, sklearn, statsmodel, seaborn, jupyter notebook
- Statistics: P-value, test for significance (z-test, t-test, chi-squared, ANOVA)
- Experimental Design: A/B testing, hypothesis testing, confidence level
- Predictive Modeling: Logistic regression, lasso, decision tree, random forest, gradient boosting
- Data Science Methods: Mining, wrangling, cleaning, analysis, visualization, storytelling
- Databases: SQL
- Languages: Fluent in English and Brazilian Portuguese

CERTIFICATES

- Data Science Career Track, 600 hours
- Data Analytics and AI Fellowship, 300 hours
- · Machine Learning with Tree-Based Models in Python
- Feature Engineering for Machine Learning in Python
- Supervised Learning with scikit-learn
- Data Visualization with Matplotlib and Seaborn
- Statistical Thinking in Python
- Data Manipulation with pandas
- Intermediate SQL
- Joining Data in SQL